So at this point this was like one bug
it could be critical already like one of
the team members found it and and filled
it as is but there was like way more to
achieve and my mind like said okay let's
see how many users are in the
organization we wanted to preesque right
so what's the best common way to preesk
from this environment let's find stale
accounts you know dead accounts maybe
with expired emails that was my thinking
h in numerating I managed to find fetch
all the users there were over 200k
accounts on that environment.
Oh my god, you're kidding.
Best part of acting when you can just,
you know, critical think, right?
Yeah,
dude.
[Music]
Sup, y'all. Before we hop into this
episode, two quick things. one, we uh
intended to do some giveaways on this
episode, but then we forgot completely
to integrate it into the episode in any
way, shape, or form. So, we're going to
make it easy for you guys. Just head
over to ctpb.show/giveaway
100. Obviously, giveaway and then
episode 100. Giveaway 100. Um, and we're
just going to make it super simple for
you to enter your name there and uh get
access to uh entering your name for the
for the giveaways that we've got. We've
going to give away some Kaido licenses.
We're going to give away um CTBB swag.
We're going to give away premium Discord
subs. And we're going to give away Shift
AI beta access. Now, that brings us to
the second point. What is Shift AI beta
access? Well, I'm glad you asked. We're
going to talk to you more about that um
at length at the end of this episode
after the uh the bug that Reszo
presents. Um but essentially the TLDDR
of it is Shift is a new Kaido plugin
that uh Joseph Dcker and I have created
and it was inspired by cursor AI. So,
I'm not sure if any of you guys have
used cursor, but it's a new IDE where um
you can just kind of prompt in natural
language what kind of app you want and
it just builds out the whole app for
you. It's phenomenal. And when we saw
this, we thought, wow, wouldn't it be
amazing if we could bring something
similar to hacking? So, that's what we
did. Uh Reszo's the backend engineer for
the AI stuff. I'm the front end for uh
Kaido integration. And we've built a
tool that can do really cool stuff like
you can paste a JS, you know, snippet in
and it will automatically generate the
replay request body that's being
described in that JS snippet. Um, you
can highlight a set of feature flags in
the response in in uh in replay in Kaido
and say, "Hey, add a match and replace
rule for me uh to turn all these feature
flags on." And boom, the match and
replace rules right in your Kaido
configuration. So, it's really great
tool. We've been loving it. We're
launching it. Um, so if you're
interested, head over to
shiftweightlist.com.
drop your email there. Um, yeah. So, two
two things. ctb.show/giveaway100
to enter the giveaways and then
shiftweightlist.com to join the wait
list for that awesome Kaido uh AI
plugin. All right, that's it. I've
ranted enough. Let's go back to the
show.
All righty, man. Here we are. 100
episodes.
You know, after 100 episodes, you still
jump up and down and get nervous before
you say,
"Dude, I do every episode. You got to
get that energy high. You got to get
that energy high. That's what the people
deserve. Join. That's what the people
deserve.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Dude, I'm I'm proud of us. 100 episodes.
Give me some, man. Give me a fist bump
through the through the screen right
now. I'm going to mess up on my camera's
focus, but
dude, um, as you guys I guess addressing
the audience, as you guys have probably
seen from the title,
we have some uh some announcements uh
today with regards to Joel. And uh Joel,
thanks so much for coming along on this
journey with me, man, for the past two
years. It's been a blast.
Yeah, absolutely. I mean, it's been
really awesome doing the podcast the
last few years. Um, you know, in terms
of why I'm leaving. It's mostly just
personal reasons. Um, you know, I wasn't
feeling super engaged with the pod. You
may have noticed I haven't been on
episodes lately. Um, it's just been sort
of difficult for me to balance
everything that I'm doing along with the
podcast. So, I think we decided that it
would be better for me to uh to step
back and uh I'll probably be on as a
guest. Uh, at least I I I know we have
one planned soon. So, so I'll definitely
be on as a guest. uh at some point. So,
I'm not going anywhere. But uh but yeah,
I will uh I will be stepping back for
the pod.
Yeah, man. You know, it's been it's been
really crazy um that you've done this
for two years in addition to full-time
job, in addition to Bug Bounty, right?
Because to in order to be able to be the
co-host of this podcast, you kind of
have to actively be like hacking on
stuff too to get the the juices flowing
and the passion, you know, running,
right? And for me as a full-time hunter,
it's easy for me to like fit that into
my schedule while doing the podcast.
But, you know, even for me, the podcast
takes up a bunch of time. Um, and I
couldn't imagine you having another
whole 40hour thing and trying to get
hacking done and trying to do the
podcast. So, dude, um, major props to
you for hanging in there for two years.
And uh
I had to get to 100, you know, get even
if I was kind of like uh being dragged
to the last
the last mile. It's like a marathon, you
know? And you got your buddy and you're
like, "Listen, we're getting over that
[__] finish line whether you like it
or not."
Oh my god, dude. [__] Joel, don't make
me laugh, man. I'm gonna I'm gonna I'm
gonna miss this, dude. I'm gonna miss
this. So, but yeah, I think it's the
right choice. I think it's the right
choice for you. I think it'll it'll um
you know make you feel less stressed.
It'll free up time. Uh allow you to
really kind of pour back into your
passions and um and yeah, I mean I think
uh the critical thinking podcast will go
on. I I hope
Yeah. Hey, it has been it has been it's
going to it's only going to keep getting
better. So um yeah, I mean I'm really
excited to see what uh what's going to
you know keep going on with the pod. Now
I get to listen to it more as like a
listener, which is fun instead of like
being
uh having the spoilers for every single
episode. So So that's fun.
Um but yeah, dude, it's been it's been
amazing and um you know, thanks for for
caring when I've been lacking and and
yeah, it's been amazing.
Of course, man. Got your back always.
And uh yeah, we'll definitely be be
having you on for guests and as a guest
and um yeah, definitely pinging you for
any uh mobile stuff that I need help
with as always.
Yeah. Cool, man. Cool. All right. So,
last episode we or hund 100th episode,
not last episode, my last episode. We've
got uh we've got a little special
something, right? So,
we got a lot on the docket. Um
what we did for this one, because we
wanted to bring you guys something
special for the hundth episode, we
reached out to Gez, how many uh how many
hackers did it end up being here? Let's
take a look. I think we have eight uh
hackers from uh critical thinking this
year that have been on the pod or been
friends of the pod. And uh we asked them
what is was your favorite bug from 2024?
Um one that you thought was creative.
Doesn't necessarily have to be the most
impactful, though most of them are very
impactful. Um and we asked those those
hackers what um you know about those
bugs to share those bugs with us and
they they kindly did. So this episode is
going to be kind of diced up a little
bit. It might be a little bit choppy
because we're going to be kind of
jumping back and forth from the time
that I recorded with these top hackers
to uh you know back today to today where
Joel and I are sort of commenting on
them. As long as Joel can hang in there.
Joel, I know you're sick right now, but
he's he's bringing his agame to the last
episode. Um so, uh let's go ahead
without further ado and jump into one of
those. First up on the list is Natalie.
Let's check out his bug from 2024.
Yep. So uh it wasn't that hard for me to
pick the biggest bug of 2024 for me
because there was only one which
actually required for me to do a lot of
steps onto it was also a collaboration
and it's like now that I started working
at we it was also pretty interesting to
see like cloud you know the world is not
only related to bug bounty and external
stuff you could also do a lot of stuff
from the inside which is interesting and
so we can get right into it and so this
was a target which allowed to hack
everything uh that belongs to the target
that that that's always good. So we
start on the internet you know like
everything is on the internet it needs
to be publicly accessible at first. Now
uh usually targets allow us to find
anything. So you have star at travel.com
this is like the code name that we that
we chose here. So what you do now you
know subdomain discovery
subfinder brute forcing fuzzing
permutations and so on and so on and so
on. If it takes you less than five
minutes, you're doing something wrong
because it should take you a lot more to
find all those assets. So that that's on
that part. So I we dive deep on that. We
found all the subdomains, a lot of
iterations, nothing really interesting,
you know, on that part.
Now we don't only have DNS assets of the
company under the root domain. There's a
lot of cloud resources that companies
use SV buckets, lambdas,
uh whatnot, azure blobs, Google storage
and so on and so on and so on. So you
know these are not really affiliated
with the company. Sometimes you can have
random naming uh arbitration like it
doesn't need to be travel. com to be
their asset. So there's a lot of ways
and a lot of tools to find cloud
resources from the outside either
references on JavaScript files from main
domains either URL scan either way
either some references that redirects
you know from different domains to cloud
domains which are not affiliated with
the company but might have data there.
Uh so that was this case we I managed to
find we managed to find one cloud
resource which didn't have the company
inside it but it had a redirection to a
domain of the company and on that domain
it was basically like
nothing your website 302 to another
domain that doesn't resolve
okay that was pretty interesting like
you get you you have a DNS that
your website that redirects to a domain
which is dead and okay so something has
to make it redirect right I mean it
wasn't just out of the blue. So it was a
C to redirect on the client side. So
whenever that happens, you have
JavaScript to examine and to look at. So
in this case, there were a lot of
JavaScript files. Usually you'd want to
look at the main main.js or like the
runtime and on Yeah, if you can stop me
if you have any question so far.
No, no, no. I I I do have I do have a
question because it's like I I'm seeing
this and and it's saying in the JS
files, so were you reaching out to that
specific cloud resource or like all
cloud resources and then if it's a
client side redirect, how how are how
the freak are you detecting this? Are
you like running all of these in like a
headless browser and seeing where you
end up? Like h how how is that
happening?
Yeah. So you can use crawling crawlers
like to fetch all the Java static
JavaScript files and then that should
give you the files already even if you
use like I think if you just use katan
or like any investing crawlers there
also there also several tools like URL
scan and others that if you search like
travel.com it shows you all the
redirections to travel.com also like
where the request originated from. So if
you look at like openai.com or like the
files like I just I was just playing
with openai I saw the file like they
save attachments on weird domain oi
private file something like that. So if
you look on this on URL scan you will
see all the websites that redirected you
to that. So you see a lot oft but you
also see some you know like cloners and
fishing domains and like chbt mockups
that they like they simulate on their
infrastructure then you can see the res
the the original resource. So what
happened here? You we searched for
domain that doesn't resolve on URL scan
and then we saw an actual Azure websites
asset that redirected to it. So that way
you can actually find cloud resources
that are not connected to the to the
asset which is pretty pretty
interesting.
That's super cool.
Yeah. So from from that point we had
JavaScript file and it had a lot of
secrets. Um so one of these secrets had
an Azure DevOps bear token which uh was
interesting to explore and we found out
in the collaboration that we can
actually invite ourselves to this
environment this company as a a guest
account on the tenant.
So as a guest account you are you have
access to the Azure ID
not much but at least I don't know if
it's default or not but we could query
like do enumeration and see all the
groups that exist and all the users that
exist just by using the Azure CLI.
I think that is default.
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. I think it's different
because you you you wouldn't expect
someone to do something with that. H so
at this point this was like one bug. it
could be critical already like one of
the team members found it and and filled
it as is but there was like way more to
achieve and my mind like said okay let's
see how many users are in the
organization we wanted to preesque right
so what's the best common way to prek
from this environment let's find stale
accounts you know dead accounts maybe
with expired emails that was my thinking
h enumerating I managed to find fetch
all the users there were over 200k
accounts on that environment
oh my god God, you're kidding me.
So all we all we have is their username,
their permissions, like which groups
they they belong to and their email
addresses. So everything is like at
travel.com, remove it. It's it's taken,
you know. So like you narrow down the
list, gmail.com, remove it and so on and
so on. Eventually, we go to a list of
like 10,000 users that have ran like
surface detection on them and like
expired domain detection to see if we
have any name servers on takeovers or we
can buy them on Gary
and around 50 domains were available for
purchase
of different it's like 100 accounts
h which was pretty interesting I mean
okay so we are now 100 accounts we need
to examine the permissions and we can
actually just reset password login and
we set up the 2FA also so No, no
restrictions on that. It was just a
story of like, you know, if they only
knew they have so many dead accounts for
like five years of some consulting
companies they use. You know, if you
look at the cloud a little bit from the
inside, if you only saw a user that now
we took over an account and it wasn't
active for six years and now it's
playing around. I mean, you know,
sunlight bulb should should burn now. I
don't know how you say it. I mean,
should spark maybe on that moment.
Yeah, absolutely. Well, it's it's crazy,
too, you know, like if you're issuing
accounts like AD accounts to like
contractors like you said, like that
that contracting company can just do
like uh a rebrand or something and now
their their domain is up for grabs and
that leads to that specific
vulnerability. So, you really need to
have a good grip on ad
hygiene uh in these sort of massive
company environments. I think
yeah I don't know how I think it's
pretty common to invite guests or like
contractors to your ad because you know
you don't want to play with like it's
octa or it's au ID it's all about
permissions you don't want to set up
account
for individuals so it's pretty
interesting I mean once you get in you
know we both experienced in Las Vegas
one night with another hunter coins that
once you get a little bit inside it's
it's yeah it's pretty it's pretty insane
where you get where you can get to yeah
privilege escalation wise so that's like
where we at now. So we found an account
that we took over the email and we saw
he had permissions to some other
applications that we knew based on the
subdomain that there was an application
with login page there with Azure. So we
wanted to try to take over that account
and log into an internal application. H
so that's what we did. We managed to log
in. didn't ask us for any 2FA and now we
got into an internal CRM application and
it looked like it was built in the 70s
and
there was nothing in the 70s but still
like it looks something like this
like you know the feeling when you log
in some
Yeah
and yeah it was wild
shag carpet everywhere shag carpet and
uh peace signs if it's from the 70s
you know the feeling when you see like
something that you say, "Okay, I I can
see the bugs already." So, you're
mentally prepared to like,
"Okay, it's it's time to walk. No more
[__] around. No more no more taking
the time."
So, straight away looking around like 10
to 15 minutes, LFI is everywhere. RC is
everywhere. SSL everywhere. Must
everywhere.
Admin Srf to Azure metadata admin
access. all the secret access h access
access to everything which is I mean you
yeah it's it's not a normal bug bounty h
story or bug because usually you stop at
the secret like you would usually stop
at the battle token obain and like hey
company I don't want to play with you
anymore you validate the critical impact
and I mean it's the same critical right
usually in terms of back bounty this
engagement they wanted us to do like hey
show us the full impact and we we'll
compensate you also if you find better
impact than the normal impact of the
back bounty.
But yeah, it's like it's not that usual,
but it's pretty interesting chain. It's
like starting from the outside with no
leads to like resources that are not
related to the company and then so many
anomalies the companies could see if
they had like there's so many points we
could have got caught you know because
it took two weeks what you see here took
two to three weeks and
it it sounds like it took five minutes
but and it takes a lot of time to then
but once you prest and get to the
internal application it's like
the GG happens very fast you know like
I think this is a really I think this is
a really good example of like how you
you get pawned in a cloud environment,
you know, like leaking those that bearer
on the outside, I think, is is one of
those one of those very very bad
mistakes where you can, you know, then
turn it from an external to an internal
and once you're already in the internal,
it's it's game over in a lot of a lot of
ways. It's just a matter of time before
you get to the the secrets of
everything. Um, so wow, dude, this is a
very impressive one. I can see why you
chose this one. This one's This one's
great.
Um, so thanks for sharing it, man.
Appreciate that.
Okay. Wow, that was uh that was cool,
man. I I hadn't heard it. I hadn't heard
that bug before from Naggley, so that's
uh it's always good. He's always got
some crazy stuff cooking,
dude. The recon game on that bug was
nuts, right? Where he is actually
identifying this leak by looking at what
assets are clientside redirecting to an
inscope asset. That is nuts. That's so
much to sift through to find this.
Yeah. Yeah, for sure.
Yeah,
it's really cool.
Um, yeah. And then I think the other
cool thing about this one is just that
you have such flexibility, right, with
this program. They're letting you sort
of pivot internally so much. You you
mostly only get opportunities like this
during pentest typically. And uh yeah,
this time they just kind of let them
have at it. So, props to the team on
that one. That one's that one's a really
cool bug that we probably wouldn't have
been able to to hear about uh if if they
weren't so permissive with their bug
bounty program. So
yeah, super cool.
All right, let's uh let's cut to the
next one. Shubs is up next, so we're
going to hear about some crazy [__] for
sure. I'm excited. I'm excited.
Yeah. Um so essentially uh if you guys
uh know my MO and my style, I mostly
focus on pre-authentication
vulnerabilities
that lead to critical serverside um
impact. Uh in this case uh this was for
a live hacking event um for for hacker 1
and uh it was a specific vendor product
which um you know has been looked at
quite heavily not just by my team at
asset note but um pretty much hundreds
of hackers over the years and and really
this vendor software um has a Linux
component or a Windows component you can
install on a server. Um it is a really
big um piece of software. It has you
know gigabytes of JAR files and things
like that. But anyways, um, in all the
different times that I've looked at this
software over the years, never been able
to find something that's
pre-authentication and can and lead to
some sort of critical impact, but this
one was particularly interesting. It was
something that required like maybe six
or different six or seven different
steps in the exploit chain to get to
command execution.
Oh my god.
And when we start off, you know, like we
we look at the process explorer, we look
at um Promon, we see what processes are
running in this vendor application and
what different technologies are there.
And, you know, it's it's a wide variety
of things in this one. There's, you
know, Apache HTTP server, there's a lot
of Java processes, and then there's, you
know, also one really peculiar NodeJS
process, which we can get into a little
bit more. Now,
now a lot of people when they ship
NodeJS serverside code for these Fender
applications, they compile it to V8 byte
code. When it is V8 byte code, it is a
pain in the ass to look at it. You you
load it into Gedra and you're like, what
am I looking at? I don't understand. And
there's there has been some developments
over time where some people have, you
know, been make have made it a little
bit easier to look at, but it's still a
total pain in the ass. And I don't think
that uh I think that the main reason why
people hadn't found stuff in this NodeJS
component is purely because they had
compiled the Node.js serverside code to
V8 by code and no one spent the time to
understand what was going on there. And
I don't blame them either. We had also
skipped this several times because we
were like we don't we don't have the
time to spend on this. The first real
breakthrough came when um came when I
realized that uh this entire component
was accessible via the HTTPD config uh
in a way that was pre-authentication and
it was responding in a way which was
basically saying like the URL is
missing. Now that's that's obviously as
you know Justin if you see something
that says that the URL is missing you
jump at that opportunity.
That is a big indicator.
That is a big indicator that
the heart starts beating fast as soon as
you see that.
Exactly. Exactly. and and you see
something like that and you're like,
"Okay, I really need to dig into this
more." And and what I found was it was a
part of some SDK that this organization
had made um to create these special
add-ons for this software. And um you
know, I just took a a little bit of a
stab in the dark and I found some SDK
documentation and a package on npm. Um I
downloaded that package and I found that
actually all of the serverside source
code for that component was within that
package, which is amazing. I mean that
that made it so much easier. Now I will
caveat that with the fact that the
serverside source code was still uh in
many ways obiscated and minified. Um so
it was still somewhat tricky to
understand but trust me I'll take
reading JavaScript over reading V8 by
code
V8 by code man I'm sure
absolutely I will take that any day of
the week. Um so yeah I started digging
into this and I started realizing that
wow this is actually a really complex
component of this application such that
it has this whole ecosystem that it
provides of this SDK and applications.
Um there were several headers that you
could provide um for this endpoint that
would essentially load um a file from
the disk um and load it into this
application SDK sandbox environment.
J must have been so hyped when you saw
this scope dude when it was starting
doing this stuff. like finally something
preoth
100%. Right.
And and that was that was really
interesting because um you know the
target we were looking at for the event
was a Linux system.
Um but really uh the reason why this
entire attack vector can be done
pre-authentication on Windows
specifically is because of the fact that
Windows allows you to provide two
backslashes uh and a uh a system volume
and then suddenly that's going to reach
out to connect via network share and
pull data from there. But essentially
there was a header that loaded a file
and on Windows obviously you can use the
network share on Linux you actually have
to have it to be a local file. Um
okay
so yeah it was it was really
interesting. So I was loading this and
this file format for all intents and
purposes was just a glorified zip file.
Um uh and inside the zip file was some
JavaScript files and a manifest file
which basically dictated what this
plugin would do. Was this supposed to be
Do you know if this API was supposed to
be used internally by the application or
whether this was something that the
client would actually hit at some point?
Yeah. Well, that's the really surprising
part. I I actually couldn't find any
legitimate use for this in any way or
form. I I I like I don't know if this
was like some rogue developers side
project that somehow got shipped to
production or there was some really
obscure feature somewhere. But to be
honest, everywhere in the application
there was zero references to this. there
was no real understanding of why this
would be used legitimately. It was some
dormant feature that had been there for
quite some time, but really didn't seem
like it it was uh actively used by the
community in any way or form. So,
definitely a little bit of dead code
there, I think. Um, but yeah, anyways,
uh that zip file, it had some it had a
manifest file, it had some other
JavaScript files, and it it started
getting me thinking like what's going on
with this? How is this executing? And um
it turns out that it was being executed
within a isolated VM sandbox which is
you know not the worst thing. It's a
good sign that your serverside code is
being executed. Good starting point
but I also know from my experience that
isolated VM when it's updated to the
newest version is actually quite tricky
to bypass and and escape.
Um I'm pretty sure that uh isolated VM
sandbox bypass escapes would be quite
valuable in any sense. So really what I
started looking at was um the first
thing I looked at was um the ability to
get SSRF because this environment was on
AWS and we could you know potentially we
could um read the metadata IP the
security credentials get access that
way. Um so started crafting that and um
what I found was the first roadblock was
I needed to somehow smuggle a zip file
uh onto the local system and know the
exact path of where that zip file was.
Um, this was a lot trickier than um,
than I thought it would be, but that was
one of the first stages was getting that
zip file there. Once I was able, right?
Like that's a big condition, but
especially if you're trying to maintain
the pre-authness of this bug, that's a
big precondition
100%. So on Windows, the the good thing
is that we can just host it on a network
share. But on Linux, we actually had to
do this in a post mechanism. So we
actually had to authenticate and then
upload the zip file in a post way. But
on Windows, you can just do a network
share and forget about all this stuff
and you can just point it to your SMB
and then get it to pull it from there.
But but on uh on this uh target for this
event we were looking at um we we were
able to get a file um in a known
location um that we were able to load
through this API endpoint and and we we
were able to achieve SSRF out of the box
quite easily. But really we wanted RC,
right? So that's that's what we always
aim for. Um so what we found was um this
isolated VM sandbox there was actually a
number of default modules that was made
available to it. Um one of them was to
load paret files and I had never been
familiar with paret files and really I I
I started digging into this more but
this is when I tapped on Riyotax's
shoulder. Now I have uh never worked
with Ryotak before but I only have some
of the best things to say about him. Um,
I was very very impressed working with
him and we had a lot of fun exploiting
this together. I know you've also had
many experiences working with him so you
would understand.
Dude, he's something else man. He really
is unbelievable. Yeah.
Unbelievable. And neither of us had
worked with paret files or duck DB or
any of these different components. But
uh we we were slowly getting there. So
what we found was it would load a paret
file and within the parket file we would
be able to basically cause a SQL
injection when it loads it into duck DB.
So they were using duct DB and they were
loading a parket file and within that
process there was a SQL injection which
we could SQL inject into duck DB. Now,
DOC DB is a relatively newish database
technology that's being used a bit more
commonly
which is really interesting because duct
DB has a lot of functionalities which I
think are inherently quite insecure. Uh
the fact like you can create files, you
can you can do all sorts of things
through duct DB that's you know quite
sensitive. Now the only reason why all
of this worked was because these modules
were being basically inherited within
the in isolated VM sandbox. So we were
using um serverside code that was
already inherited in the isolated VM
sandbox that could let us escape the
sandbox essentially.
So this is this is how it worked.
But we still had a few more roadblocks.
So we basically construct a zip that has
park file that loads park file from a
URL that then leads to the SQL injection
that then leads to duct DB doing
something naughty. But what actually
happened was we weren't able to get Duck
DB to execute that injected SQL uh when
we loaded into DuckDB. Now that was
probably because we weren't actually
triggering that portion of SQL that we
had injected.
So what we had to do then is we had to
leverage the first SSRF we had in this
chain uh to communicate to a different
port on the server which was responsible
for managing duct DB and then trigger a
refresh or a load of that table inside
Duck DB which would then lead to the far
right.
Oh my gosh. It's almost like a it's like
a delayed SQL injection there.
That's right. We do need that second
step to get that SQL injection to
trigger. Go. So we were able to get
there but the problem was um where do we
write to? Now this was a this was a
modern Java application and a lot of
modern Java applications they don't
actually have JSP handlers. They they
basically like if you look at any modern
Spring Java application they don't
actually need to have the ability to
process and and render JSP files. So
this modern Java application, we go
through these several different web apps
inside the Tomcat directory and we we we
really struggle to find a location to to
write this uh JSP shell um which we
thought was the most logical way to
exploit this
which you got from the arbitrary right
on duct. Okay, got
yeah that's right. So at this point
we've got an arbitrary file right
through many many different stages of
exploitation but we don't know where to
write the file to get the command
execution. So that's kind of where we
were stuck on for a little bit. And what
we found was um in in uh in Tomcat in
web XML files sometimes there is a
specific handler um for exceptions and
this was one of the only locations that
we found where we could exploit this. Um
there was this for one of the web
applications there was a handler for 500
uh for 500 errors for exceptions that
was pointing to a JSP file inside one of
the tag library uh tag library folders.
So what we did was we replaced that JSP
file that was a handler for 500
exceptions and we replaced that with our
shell and then we um uh then we
basically uh uh exploited this by
triggering a 500 error in the
application that then triggered our
arbitrary code from that whole process.
So at the end uh we had command
execution but that was that was the
chain. Um, so I don't know if you have
any questions or any any uh comments on
this chain.
Yeah. So, so one, it's crazy that at the
end it's like, okay, now I need to
trigger a 500 error. Like now I've got
to find some unhandled exception that
just screws this whole system up.
That's crazy. Okay, so I'm trying to
trying to follow with all of this. Just
I'm going to try to recap it a little
bit here and you you you catch me where
I I I get it wrong. Okay, so we find
this this um compiled Node.js JS uh
binary that is is you know mapped to a
specific route. You hit that you can hit
it on authenticated. You can upload a
zip file. That zip file will run JS code
in isolated VM. And then from there we
are trying to we need to have that the
code inside of that um run something
that triggers the SQL injection. So
that's the part where you lost me.
Yeah. So basically there are a lot of
default functions within this SDK. One
of those functions is to load a paret
file
and when it loads the paret file from a
URL, it will then load it into duct DB
and that's where you got the SSRF. Okay,
so it loads the paret file from the and
that's why
No, that's why I got the SQL injection.
So the SSRF is separate as well.
Oh my gosh,
it's such a complex bug. Yeah, it's such
a complex bug. No, I apologize. So
basically, you've you've got a you
you've got a endpoint that loads a zip
file that then runs inside an isolated
VM. you can achieve SSRF quite easily.
Um, but we want to escape the isolated
VM to get command execution. So the way
we do that is let's just say we already
have our SSRF ready on one side ready to
go.
Now now we load a second zip file which
does loads the paret that loads the duck
DB SQL injection. Then we use that first
SSRF to trigger that SQL injection uh
through a different port that then
refreshes that duct DB table and that
lets us write anywhere on the system.
Um, and then when we want to write on
the system, we got to find a place. And
since it's a modern Java application,
the only location we could find was a
exception handler within the web XML.
And rewriting that 500.jsp,
which was to handle 500 exceptions, and
then triggering a 500 exception would
lead to the RC. Yeah.
Okay. Okay. So, I'm going to try to
recap it here. I think I think I got
this. So, we uh find the the route, the
unauthenticated route. We upload to
there. Then there's some sort of SDK
where you can trigger the parsing of a
park parquet file. Is that right?
Yeah. And then that that you get the SQL
injection from there, but it's time it's
delayed. It needs to be triggered. So
you use the SSRF to trigger that SQL
injection that gets you arbitrary file
right and then you write into the JSP
file. Oh my gosh.
Yeah, it's a it's it's definitely one of
my favorite bugs by far and you know
it's it's pretty crazy. Um,
how did you end up triggering the 500?
Uh, we uh
without giving too much information away
on the target.
No, we we we caused a null pointer
exception uh within the application to
to trigger the 500. Yeah.
And um it was also funny cuz the
application was load balanced, so you
had to hit it five or 10 times before
you got the shell to show up.
Of course, for for just for the heck of
it there, just add that extra variable
to it. Wow, dude. That is a crazy bug
and a masterpiece. So, thank you for
sharing that with us, man.
Uh, no problem. And yeah, just want to
give a shout out to Riyot Attack as well
who worked on this with me. Um, very,
very enjoyable process and I think uh,
he'll remember this one fondly as well
for the years to come.
Dude, typical subs,
dude. I'm literally just sitting here
still after listening to that again and
just being like, wow, what an absolute
masterpiece, man. the the the the time
delayed, you know, SQL injection. What
is that, man?
It's so crazy. It's so crazy.
That's nuts, dude. Wow. Um well,
definitely shout out to Shubs on that
one. That was uh amazing. And of course,
Odo Tuck as well. Great work, gentlemen.
Great work. All right, next one up is uh
is Matt Brown. Let's go see what he's
got.
So NTP is a a bug and and NTP issues are
a bug class that uh some people uh find
impactful, some people don't, but there
I find them interesting uh because I
like to go back to my roots of looking
at data as it goes across the wire. So
uh so this bug that I found uh was on a
uh an IoT device that had parental
controls, right? So a parent could hand
this device to their child and they
could uh browse, you know, a a limited
set of media and they could do that in a
safe way. And the other thing parents
could do, there was this feature where
they could set a bedtime
and they and so during a certain time as
a as a parent, you know, I'm I'm drawn
to these kind of features, right? Right.
And so uh so there was a feature in this
device where you could set a bedtime
where all of the media would be disabled
uh during the bedtime. And so any time
where an application is telling you no
because of what time it is, uh Douglas
Day has this great talk where he talks
about looking for the nos in an
application.
What a legendary talk, dude. That talk
was so good.
It's so simple and yet so profound. And
so what I guess I'm introducing here is
one of the ways that an application can
tell you no is by what time it is.
Is by when is is is is when is a is is a
way that an application can tell you no.
And so if that is occurring especially
in a mobile app or an IoT device then
you have to ask where is it getting that
time data from right
so uh NTP is the most common protocol
you see to uh acquire uh time data and
so it's one of two protocols actually in
2024 that by and large is still flying
around the internet unencrypted
unauthenticated right
love that
yeah yeah it's great and the other one
it's interesting it's actually an
interesting the use case. The other one
is DNS.
But DNS, we just assume that it's not
trusted and then we do things like
certificate verification to to to get to
build trust on top of something that's
not trustworthy, right? And so, uh, on
this device, I was able to a spoof NTP.
I was able to spoof what time it is. And
to do this, I use a tool called
Delorean. Uh, and so, you know, aptly
named, right?
Solid. I can see where they got it.
Yeah. If you're if you're doing some
time travel, you got to use Delorean.
And so, uh, all it is is it's just a
spoofed, you know, NTP server that you
can intercept the NTP traffic with and
provide whatever time you want.
And so on this on this IoT device, we
were able to uh bypass the bedtime for
for for the child by uh by spoofing that
it was like the middle of the day when
the bedtime was set for nighttime,
right? uh and then you're able to bypass
those uh those parental controls in that
way. And so if you're not a parent, you
might not think that that's like a cool
threat model, but I've found similar
threats in things like smart locks
where a smart lock will have a feature
where you can have a pin that you set
for your cleaning person, right? And so
that pin will only let them in at a
certain time or a certain day. And so,
uh, in that situation, uh, it's it's the
same exact bug, but the threat model is
interesting because, uh, those people
you're letting into your home, they
might actually have access to your Wi-Fi
network. And, and so the attack becomes
a lot more realistic.
Yeah, that makes a lot of sense actually
in that in that threat model where they
have they're allowed access to to your
home, but only at a certain time. And so
they have access to things that would
allow them to perform this
man-in-the-middle attack and then be
able to trick the lock or whatever thing
it it is into thinking it's a different
time.
Dang, dude. That is a pretty unique
attack vector.
Hell yeah. I mean, it's so it's so cool.
I love um I love that Douglas's talk
always keeps coming up in all these
different people's things whether it's
at Nom Con or at this or I mean we we
talked to Douglas directly about it.
Um yeah, finding those nos it's it's
very very consistent.
Yeah. And it's it's so applicable across
uh so many different scopes, right? You
know, you can apply it to pretty much
anything. Um such a simple concept. It's
just those those really nice little
simple concepts that really just resound
with you, I think.
Yeah, totally
solid. All right. Well, up next is uh
somebody who's been on the pod a lot
lately. I've been like I've been
squeezing this guy for some content,
man. Really like he's just got so much
good stuff. So, let's uh let's go see
what Matan Bear has for us as for a bug
for this year.
So, um, this one was in a very big site
that I won't name and because the bug is
going to come out soon because that site
I think is going to disclose it, but um
I'm still exploiting bypasses and stuff.
So,
um, this was a very complicated bug in
the way that site rendered markdown. So
um there was some sort of scenario where
an attacker could make
um the site render malicious markdown in
sort of the v the victim's browser or
the victim's context.
Okay. And that scenario, the way they
rendered the markdown was pretty
complicated because they wanted to allow
the markdown to load images and stuff
like that from specific sources that
otherwise it wouldn't have access to.
Sorry for having it be um a little
vague, but yeah, I'm trying to work
around the um actual mentions of what
the target is. I I appreciate you
agreeing to disclose it even though
you're still actively uh milking it. Um
and and for those as well listening, we
have uh some graphics up on YouTube as
well if this complicate the complicated
explanation doesn't make sense just over
audio.
Honestly, it was so complicated I made
the graphics for myself so I could keep
track of things.
That's great.
It definitely took me a while to figure
that one out. M
so the sort of um
the way they rendered the markdown
um they had like the
um top window like the top frame and
that uh frame didn't do a lot of stuff.
The actual frame that had most of the
context, most of the content was just an
I frame inside that window that was like
full screen. And I called that uh frame
the main frame. Okay. Then inside that
frame, there was sort of a bridge frame
that had like a different origin. So if
the main frame was like redacted.com,
this was like some weird subdomain.
Reductor.com, right? And then inside
that
bridge frame, there was a sandbox frame
with the same like weird subdomain.
Origin. Okay.
Okay. Okay. So, we've got top frame
that's on redacted.com. Main frame
inside of that which is on redacted.com.
Then we've got the bridge frame on some
uh weird origin. And then we inside of
that we've got the sandbox frame also on
some weird origin.
Yeah, we're four layers deep.
Four layers deep. Let's go. So the role
of like the bridge frame was to sort of
bridge the communication between the
sandbox frame and the main frame.
Okay. And the sandbox frame frame is
just where the malicious HTML is
rendered.
Okay. So because malicious HTML is
rendered in the sandbox frame, it's very
trivial to or at least it was very
trivial to get XSS on it. Okay, you can
just run JavaScript in there now. and it
was allow allow scripts was enabled on
the on the sandbox.
Yeah, you could just run JS like very
simple.
Um they just thought that it wouldn't
have impact but um and like in and of
itself the um excss in that subdomain
actually didn't have a lot of impact. Um
but there was a feature that I mentioned
that allowed the um markdown inside the
sandbox frame to load
uh assets say like images
um from like the actual site. So from
like reductor.com. So if there's an
image that only the victim can access,
the markdown can load it. Okay. So now
there's already an impact that you can
see like if the markdown can render that
image. So you have an attack scenario
where if you know like the path to the
image you can render it and then from
the JavaScript execution that you have
you can get the cont content of the
image
but I wasn't very satisfied with that
because that's a pretty lame attack
scenario.
So I looked into how the actual loading
of the image works and that's very
interesting. So the way it worked and
sorry for the graphic being a little
complicated.
Gosh.
But um the sandbox frame sends an HTTP
request, right? To load the image or
something like that.
Okay.
And that request gets intercepted by a
service worker
that lives on that frame. Okay. That
service worker then sends a message to
the bridge frame letting it know that
the sandbox frame just tried to load a
an image or something like that from
this specific path. Okay. Then the
bridge frame forwards that message to
the main frame.
Okay. And then the main frame does some
validation on the URL that you try to
load. So if that URL is like um under I
don't know reductor.com/im images, okay,
there was like a bunch of um specific
paths that it could have been under.
Then it would actually send the request
and then forward the response back to
the bridge frame. And now all of the
forwarding happens in reverse. So the
bridge frame forwards the response back
to the service worker which forwards it
back to the sandbox frame. So you've got
like request being sent from the sandbox
frame to the service worker to the
bridge to the main frame. Then some
validation then um a response is is sent
back to the bridge frame and then to the
service worker and then to the sandbox
frame.
Okay. Okay. So we we've created almost a
proxy at this point, right? From the
sandbox frame origin
back up through the main frame with some
validation and then back down to the
sandbox frame.
Exactly.
Okay.
So of course I tried messing a little
with the validation. But the problem was
that um
if I try to do and this is a bit of a
spoiler but a path reversal.
Mhm.
Okay. I can't really do that with this
um with this setup because if I send a
request that has like a path traversal
in its um in its URL, it's going to get
normalized by the browser before it even
reaches the service worker,
right? On the on the original request
that was that was sent before it hits
the service worker. Okay.
So what I did here because the sandbox
frame and the bridge frame are same
origin.
I could just from the sandbox frame hop
here and start executing JS here. Okay.
Oh my gosh, dude. What?
This is the most funny part of the whole
bug.
Maybe they thought of that. Maybe it was
from for for some other reason. But in
the sandbox frame, they overridden
window. To be null.
So you couldn't do like parent evil or
something like that.
Okay. Sure.
But I just went like top frames dot
whatever.
Sure. And you can just traverse down
from top.
Okay.
Or if that uh if top was also overridd
then I probably could have um
open. Yeah. Open and then parent or
Yeah. A million ways. So um that's like
not actual isolation. M
once I had a JS execution in the bridge
frame I tried to find some way that I
can hijack this communication. So the
way this communication
communication meaning the communication
between the bridge frame and the main
yeah I forget that um not everyone is
watching on YouTube.
Yeah. So um the communication between
the bridge frame and the main frame the
way it worked is that the main frame
sent a
a message port to the bridge frame and
they communicated via that message port.
Okay. So both had like access to some
message port that they sent messages
through. So what I did once I had um JSX
execution in the bridge frame, I
overrode
the um prototype of message port. Okay.
Oh my god.
So the function that is responsible for
sending messages through message ports
is messageport.prototype.post
message. And when you have some port say
like P1 and you do P1.post post message
the function that actually gets called
is that um prototype function. M
so if I override it then I can when such
a call is made p1 um post message my
malicious function is going to get
called
and if you're familiar with JavaScript
the this uh the value of the this
variable when my function gets called is
going to get is going to be P1
right so long to the message port
yeah long story short I overriding some
function in JavaScript,
I could get access to the message port
um that is used for this communication,
meaning the communication between the
bridge and the main frame.
Um whenever the bridge frame sends a
message, so I could just override that
prototype, trigger some action that
makes it send a message. in this case
like um calling fetch from the sandbox
frame
because that whole communication is
going to forward it
right.
Um so now I had access to the message
port okay
and I could send um like
raw communication to the main frame. I
didn't have to go through the browser's
parsing of URLs. So what I try to do now
is path traversal. Okay, because I
mentioned that there were like a bunch
of root paths that were allowed in the
um in the validation that the main frame
does on the URL. Um and
quite surprisingly actually they checked
whether the um the paths had
do/sequences.
Okay.
Wow. Okay.
Yeah. which it's that's impressive
because it isn't often that people
actually think of that
and especially when there's this sort of
complex communication,
right?
But and they didn't consider
backslashes.
Yeah, I knew it, dude. I knew it. As
soon as you said that, I was like, but
they didn't get the backslash, did they?
So many pitfalls in that. Yeah.
Oh my god. Uh, so I could send like a
request to reductor.com
and by request I mean like a message
that represents a request too.
um redacted.com/
images or whatever whitelisted root path
and then dot dot backslash
and um a bunch of backslashes and then I
could just send requests as the
um victim like make the main frame send
requests to whatever path under
reductor.com
okay
and that just led to account takeover
and then at that point I mean do Do you
have like uh control of like the object
that gets passed into like the request
initiator object or something like that?
So you can specify like post, you know,
mode is post or whatever and include
credentials and that sort of thing.
I I had a ton of um a ton of control.
Wow, dude. like yeah that is a good
question because it isn't completely
expected if you strictly looking at the
case of images but I think that because
with images you're only going to need
like get requests with nobody
right
um but I think they tried to make this
setup a little more generic and I'm not
sure for which use case but yeah that
just was in there um
wow so then so Then you were able to
send a message from the bridge frame to
the main frame that would just trigger
account takeover on the application.
So I sent a request that uh that was
like a get request to some endpoint.
Then I got the CSRF token back from that
because I can read the responses, right?
Then I sent another one um a post that
did some change on the account and with
um with the correct CSRF token and that
was just account takeover.
Oh my god, Matan. Dude, that's crazy. I
love I love the trick the prototype
pollution trick, right? Where you um
override the prototype because that
getting a reference to that message port
would have been a massive pain in the
ass. uh you know, but you can just
overwrite the prototype, snag it right
as it's going through, and then now
you've got access to that one side of
the can, right, that we always talk
about when we when we talk about message
ports.
Yeah, I like that you started using my
analogy.
It's great, dude. It's a it's a great
analogy for that for sure. So that that
trick of like when you get JS execution
in some context and you want to get
access to some secret or something like
that
overriding prototypes is actually more
generic than you might expect.
I had one case on a completely different
target where I could like
um or actually let me give a theoretical
um example that would be more
interesting. Say you have like self
excesss on some site. I know that I talk
about self excesss too much but
dude that's like your [__] but whatever.
It's like
I don't want to be known as self excesss
guy that
hey the guy that turns self xss into
real excss. It's pretty good.
Yeah. Every self excss that I touch
turns into gold.
Yeah.
Some [__] into gold.
You're going to get a [__] ton of DMs
now being like I've got self excesss
when I paste this thing into this thing.
That was a mistake. Yeah.
Yeah. Um, so say you have a self
exercise on some site.
Okay.
Right. And you can't use the trick that
we talked about in our pod episode to
convert that selfs into a regular xss.
Sure. So the um
conventional way of exploiting that
would be you have some um page and then
you open you like from the attacker site
open a page to um target.com right when
the victim is still logged into their
account then you make them logged in log
into your account trigger the self
accesss and then execute JavaScript in
the page that you opened originally.
Right.
So,
what's interesting is if that site
target.com
um uses like
um access tokens instead of cookies for
um authentication to the API. Okay. if
they store those access tokens
um like in memory in their fetch
implementation in some variable.
What you can do is actually um after you
make them log into your account and uh
start executing JavaScript in the um
target.com
page. Okay, like the original one that
has the victim's account.
um the access token to the victim's
account is still going to be in memory.
And when you trigger some action that um
triggers communication with the API, the
fetch is still going to contain the
access token, right?
Wow. Yeah.
So what you can do is override the fetch
function,
trigger that action
on opener window. So do like like
on the Yeah. on the window that has the
um
the victim session or whatever
authenticated window let's call it.
Yeah.
Wow.
The off window you can override the
fetch function trigger an action that um
makes the page communicate with the API
and then catch that um that token from
memory.
Wow, dude. That's crazy. And and as long
as it doesn't reload it from local
storage or whatever or or then you're
good. or maybe they have it in session
storage. And even if it does, um,
right? Something that does that won't
get updated when you make them log out
from their account.
Wow, dude. You're like the self access
master, man. There's so many different
selfs techniques you drop on this pod,
man. Dude, all that client side stuff
just it makes me so excited. I I can see
that you understood all of that, right,
Joel?
That made my brain hurt.
That made my brain hurt. I'm looking at
the I'm looking at the diagram of this
and it still makes my brain hurt.
It's It's crazy, dude. He's He's really
something else, that guy.
It's crazy. It's crazy. Cool. All right.
Well, now we've got one from our boy.
Speaking of Douglas Day,
Mr. Douglas Day.
Um, you know, speaking of the nose and
all that, we've got uh we've got one
from the man himself. So, let's let's
listen.
Yeah. So, the bug I'm most uh proud of
for 2024 happened a while back. I was
hacking on a company and they had a
pretty wide scope and they had a
subdomain which was exclusively used to
advertise and uh broadcast events that
were happening within that uh that uh
company's product. And so uh on that on
that uh subdomain I see a little
calendar at the bottom and it's like
talking about future events that they're
going to be uh streaming or
broadcasting. Um, and I'm like, and I
had this itch go off in my head. I'm
like, "Oh, how cool would it be if I
were able to make my own events and put
them on their calendar, you know? I like
not many people like come to my birthday
party." And I'm like, "What if I got
this entire company's like user base to
show up at my birthday party?" You know,
I'd be like so many presents. I'd get a
lot of like happy birthdays. It'd be
awesome. So, I'm like, "Okay, I want to
make my birthday be a public event for
this company, right? So, how do I do
that?" So, I pull up Kaido and I'm
looking at the request history and I see
that when that calendar loads, it makes
a request to a third party or in this
case a third party really um uh that is
a online streaming service uh that that
companies can use to like host their
their broadcast. I'm like, "Okay, this
actually sounds pretty interesting." Um,
so I I do some googling on this on this
third party and I see that it has a free
self-signup and I'm like, okay, what if
I can get like what if I can make my own
organization and then find some IDOR?
Um, and so I created my own account on
the streaming service uh with my own
website that had, you know, just garbage
data and I found the spot to make like
events and and videos and I made my own
and uh and it did use a UU ID and so I
was initially a bit discouraged. I'm
like, oh, this is an unguessable ID,
but because the the victims or my my
targets uh subdomain was public, like
when it when it pulls those events, it's
pulling it with the with the U ID. So, I
have it. That's public information. So,
I go and I try the UU ID and sure
enough, there's an ID door there. I can
like modify modify videos and events.
I'm like, "Okay, this is cool. This is
pretty like untouched. Like, this is
pretty exclusive scope. Let's let's go
further." Um, and so I start testing
every piece of functionality. I'm like,
"Okay, there's Najor there. There's
Najor here. There's Najor there. Oh,
there's
the golden goose, dude."
Yeah. Yeah, I did. I did. Cuz I was I'm
the only one hacking on this on this uh
particular app, right? Cuz it's a third
party. I don't even think I had asked
the uh the customer yet if it was a shot
here, right? Like I I this is going to
be in scope. I hope they're going to pay
for this.
Yeah. And that's that's kind of how you
got to do it, right? Like when when
hacking on bug bounty, like the skill is
not finding bugs. Like you can learn how
to find bugs.
The skill like the real skill is finding
scope.
And so I'm like, okay, this is scope
that no one else has touched. If I if I
can get this to be paid, then this is
going to you I'm going to be sitting
real happy. So anyh who, I'm like, okay,
I've got Naidor everywhere. I've got XSS
that I can IDOR. So I can like it's a
self XSS, but I can like turn it into I
can chain it with an IDOR to basically
deliver an XSS onto the onto my targets
uh website. Uh what else can I do? And
I'm like, okay, what if I can just like
go for the, you know, shoot for the
stars and get an atto.
So I'm like, okay, there's uh there's of
course the functionality to invite other
like users or admins to your
organization. So my first my first idea
is okay what if I can like invite a an
existing user into my org. You know can
you exist in more than one or uh it
turns out you can't. But uh when you
when you add someone to your
organization there's two ways to do it.
You can either send them an email and of
course I'm not going to have access to
the email so I can't use that or you can
give them a link and uh to to click on
and then go through the go through the
off flow there. So I'm like okay. So, I
invite I invite um but but the link is
tied to that user's uh email address.
And so, I find out who the who the admin
is on my targets organization.
I add them as a as an admin to my
organization, but because I don't have
access to their email, I just copy the
link, go and go into a incognito window,
go through the the off flow, accept the
invite. Uh now that user is now
simultaneously both in their
organization and my organization.
What?
But because they're in my organization,
I can change their email address. And so
I change their email address to an email
that I control and then I go through the
password reset flow to reset their
password and then be able to log into
the victim's uh victim's organization.
So at that point,
it was an arbitrary ATO. This wasn't
like I thought you were going to chain
like the the ID door with XSS into like
an ATO, but it still required them to
like at least log into the app. But this
one is just arbitrary ATO.
Yeah. As long as you have their email.
As long as I did have to play a bit of a
game where I was like having to like
scroll through social media and like
message people on LinkedIn like
oh what if I'm I found an issue with
this particular website. Can you let me
know what there like that that services
admin email it is? But I couldn't I
couldn't actually
couldn't find it. So, I eventually had
to get the Bug Bounty team to tell me
who their who their admin for this
particular site was.
But yeah, it was a a zero click atto
just a all I needed was their email
address. Then I could invite them to my
org and then change their email address
and then change their password. And then
I got Yeah. So I got access to their
org. And that opened up even more scope
because then I could look for like
privilege escalations. I could look for
features that weren't like enabled and
and enable those. I could um uh like
change billing information. It was yeah
it was a it was a very it was a very
impactful bug I think including the
bonus
did they pay for pay for all of those or
did they dup them all back or how did it
work? they duped each. So I being a bug
bounty hunter, I of course try to
maximize my like maximize my profit,
right? And so I filed every like
endpoint as a different report, right?
As well as each HTTP verb. And so of
course, you know, I would like if I
could modify on, you know, slashevents,
I would file that as a bug. If I could
delete events, I file that as a bug. If
I could retrieve private events, I'd
file that as a bug. And they did keep
the different endpoints separate, but
then they lumped uh the different
function. Yeah. All the verbs together.
I feel like that's a good option, right?
Because it's like you submit all of
those and then they sort of meet you in
the middle, right? Whereas if you had if
you had just submitted each individual
endpoint, then they might have been
like, "Okay, well, we're just going to
dupe it down to two reports, but now you
got
Exactly.
I I think it's good. I think it's a good
strategy,
dude. Classic green hat move from our
boy Douglas there, huh? It's like, you
know me, I'm going to maximize my
profit.
Every single HTTP verb at every single
end point. It's great. I mean, hey,
that's the way.
You're not a full-time bug bounty hunter
if you haven't done that. That's what
I've come to realize. That's the big
difference.
Yeah. It's interesting, too, that he he
spent a lot of time, you know, going
down that rabbit hole of even though it
was a third party app, you know. Uh I
think in this scenario, I think he
probably trusted the program that they
would pay based off of impact. That's a
pretty scary thing to do, I think.
Yeah, for sure. For sure. But another
cool bug, of course.
Indeed. All right, let's uh let's hop
next over to AJ Chapman.
Oh, man. So, this was uh this was just
one of those really frustrating bugs
that I that I came across. So um I was
kind of in between programs looking for
something new to new to hack on and I
saw a program that I've been wanting to
hack on for a while but they had codello
bounty table
so I hadn't looked them up to that point
but then I noticed they had a three
three times multiplier on critical
reports for like 10 days brilliant this
gives me the opportunity to actually
actually spend time there.
Obviously I kind of noticed this with
two days left of the promotion to go.
Um,
but screw it. I can find a critical in
two days. So, kind of bring it up. And
obviously, what bugs do I look for? I
exploit serverside Chrome. That's pretty
much all I do anymore. Um, so the first
thing I do, I see this kind of fancy
dashboard um system and you can export
the dashboard as a PDF. It's definitely
using a serverside browser to do that.
So, um, kind of set up a dashboard,
export that, and check for the, uh,
check the PDF metadata, and that's where
you can tell if it's using kind of
Chrome or, uh, WK HTML to PDF or
something like that. So, if you check
the, uh, creator or producer um, PDF
metadata options, that will tell you
what it's using and normally the precise
version it's using. Uh, which is great.
So, in this case, it was using Chrome
um, Chrome 1119, which was perfect. I
had an exploit in the in the bag already
for Chrome 1119 and thought great good
to go. So let's let's see what I can do.
The only problem is this was not meant
to execute kind of user pride
JavaScript.
So I was going to try and find the
crossite scripting.
Now I am I've said it before and I will
say it again. I'm the worst web app
tester. I hate it. I've got no interest
in it whatsoever.
But you you really need those XSS's for
your for your vol. So
yeah, tell me about it. tell me about
it. So, I kind of sat down and uh and
thought like normally I would give up,
but there was this three times cry [__]
promotion um on this and I thought, you
know what, I'm I'm going to get this.
I'm I'm going to exploit this one. So,
sat down there with the kind of started
looking through the minified JavaScript
and realized I'm not going to get
anywhere with that. So threw it into
Claude um see what it could come up with
and kind of notice you could add rich
text elements to these to these
dashboards. So you could add um
descriptions of your graphs and all the
rest of it um including rich text. So
that's normally a pretty good pretty
good place for injecting HTML.
Mhm.
Um so kind of have a look at that and
obviously it's protected using DOM
purify. Great. Okay. What version?
Latest version purify game over.
All right, fine. Look around. Look
around. Then I did that thing that all
kind of
newbie hackers do as I I went to a
GitHub gist full of XSS payloads and
thought, here we go. Throw that at it.
See if anything sticks. Obviously,
nothing happened.
Um kind of start keyboard mashing a
little bit. Just throwing in anything I
could. and uh notice that if you added
um text URLs, they got linkified. So it
became click clickable links. I was
like, well, I didn't add an a tag. I
didn't add the required HTML to do that.
So, uh so kind of delved into that a
little bit more and found they were
actually editing the
input HTML after it'd been through the
DOM purify stage.
Oo, nice. Now I don't know a huge amount
about XSS but I know that's bad. Editing
sanitized JavaScript is a bad thing.
So what they were doing they were taking
anywhere so throw your input through DOM
purify and then anywhere it found a reax
for URL it would replace that with the a
tag href equals your URL and then the
URL and the text um portion of the a
tag. So kind of bought up the um
various payloads on uh
exercise payloads to kind of kind of
look at this and I came across this one.
Um the other thing is obviously uh it
being a serverside browser. Sorry,
jumping back a bit.
I couldn't use an on click event or
anything like that. Had to had to happen
automatically as soon as the page was
loaded.
Right. Right. So I think using the the
portiger XSS cheat sheet came across
this details tag um with the open ele um
open attribute
and if that's if that exists the the on
toggle um event handler for that element
will fire. So okay kind of starting to
piece it all together now. So came up
with this with this input tag which was
uh details with the open attribute and
then an arbitrary attribute name. In
this case, it was called X with my with
a crafted
um with the crafted link in it which
went through DOM purifier give or take
unmodified
and then when it was applied to the link
fire script, it then was able to escape
out of the arbitrary attribute I gave it
into an on toggle um attribute for the
details element and kind of um trigger
the trigger the event. And
dude, you you say you're not a web
hacker. That's a pretty elite flow,
dude. That's freaking sick.
That took me a long time. I hate to
admit it, but uh Oh, I was pretty like
pretty chuffed with myself on this.
But you made it you made it inside of
the the critical deadline. Yeah.
Yeah. So, this I think had about 8 hours
to go at this point. So, I've got my
XSS. I've got my my uh pre-written
exploit in the bag. Kind of link it all
up. XS payload to inject an iframe.
export the PDF and nothing happened.
No. No.
Seriously, I'm sitting there waiting for
this this shell back or these shell
commands back and nothing happened. Like
literally got eight hours to get this
report in to to be in the uh the
campaign deadline. And I just stopped
panic debugging like what is going on?
what was and I must have thrown probably
200 PDF requests at the at the app from
from this point just trying to work out
what was going on.
Um, and then eventually realized that in
the back end the the web browser
disabled web assembly
and the the exploit I was using uh CV
2024 uh 2887 is a is a web assembly bug.
Oh [__] Okay.
So I'm trying to like trying to throw
this thing at it and it just wasn't
going to work. So, all right. Okay.
Kind of give up in a bit of a huff. I'm
like, "No, no, come on. I we can do
this. We can do this.
Let's go. Let's go. Come on."
So, start I found some I believe it was
a Taiwanese blog um detailing an another
um Chrome exploit for for that version
and like throwing it through Google
Translate trying to find as much
information as I could. Kind of I think
it was getting late at night at this
point as well. So, a couple of coffees
in just like panic writing um this
exploit trying to get it to work and it
worked locally. I'm like, "Yes,
brilliant. This is good." Throw it up.
Doesn't work. Okay.
No, not dead.
Doesn't work. Refresh. Doesn't work.
Like the fourth or fifth time it worked.
I'm like, "Okay, so it's
it's an unstable exploit, but I got it."
And and I got the command output and I'm
like, "This is like fantastic." about an
hour to go before the the campaign
deadline, like wrote the worst report of
my life, like RCE here. Um, kind of
submit and and got it in.
Gosh, dude.
Um, and it literally one of the
reproduction steps was you might need to
run it 20 to 30 times for it to actually
do anything, but but it will.
Um, kind of the so got that in campaign
deadline finished up. Um, and then
obviously I went back afterwards to try
and improve the report because it was uh
was in a terrible terrible state. Um,
and then kind of cleaned up the exploit
after that. It kind of felt like um I
don't know how you were at um college or
in school, but it felt like a school
deadline.
Oh my god.
Or college deadline, like up all night
trying to get it done.
Um, finally got in like massive relief.
Um,
dude,
came out of it with a 6K bounty. Not
certainly not the best bounty of my
life, but by the time I was I was in too
deep to to to back off.
Yeah, it seems like it. And it's crazy
to me that cuz I was just about to say
like, oh, it's good that you have all
these exploits and such in the back
because it's like, oh, you didn't have
any time to develop a new Chromium
exploit, right? But actually, that's
exactly what you had to do.
Yeah, in that case, I I' now have like
two or three exploits for most the
versions I I target on Chrome just in
case. But um
yeah.
Yeah, that was a fun one.
Name something more iconic than Alex
Chapman and a Chrome bug.
I know, dude. I know. It's crazy to me
that he not only found the XSS in that
short time frame and a pretty elite like
Don Beirify bypass XSS. Um but also had
to rewrite the whole V8 exploit again.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Absolutely nuts, man. Absolutely nuts.
So, props to you, Alex. That was that
was pretty crazy. All right. Up next,
none other than Mr. Ben Namsk himself.
Let's see what he's got. All right, man.
So, it looks like from the doc, we are
talking about uh some of the craziness
that happened surrounding 702 where you
walked out with the belt and something
like six rces. So, hit me with your
favorite uh your favorite bug story.
Honestly, man, I don't think there's a
favorite bug story. That entire event
was unreal from how it started and how
it went. It was just insane. Just
I'll give you a background story. You
know, the the kickoff calls happened,
right? And we all set up the kickoff
calls and like
I did last 702 before it solo showed up
solo and I ended up like top four or top
five bounty earners
which was massive, right?
You're going massive with like this this
bag of cash on your shoulder. You go
great. Yeah.
But there is there is some cool stuff. I
mean, I'm not going to cry in a corner
with all the cash that I've made, but
also like there's a lonely aspect to
that, right? Like you're hacking solo
when you're hacking, you know, you you
know, I'm going against France Rosen and
Matias. I'm going against Zano and
Bowman and then you have P4FG, right?
They're just popping random things,
right? Like just keeping up.
Um there's a there's a solo aspect of it
that I don't enjoy. I really genuinely
enjoy hacking with people. And
I think when I have somebody, it doesn't
have to be like we're splitting
everything, but if I have somebody there
telling me like, "Hey, I'm doing this
thing. Do you want to contribute to it
or do you want to look at it together?"
It really helps you motivated because
they're finding things. You can find
something based on them. That energy is
what I wanted. Right.
So,
they announces Tik Tok and Epic. I go,
"Dude, I can't I hate both of those
programs."
I I go, Justin's going to crush Epic
because I know you've been hacking on
Epic a lot. Yeah. I go, I gota compete
against someone that already hacks Epic
a lot of times.
And then it's Tik Tok, a public program
that I've been wanting to hack on, but I
never could find anything, dude. I then
I didn't show up to 702, not ever
hacking on TikTok. I've done maybe like
I don't know 30 hours of hacking on
TikTok at this point.
So I'm like, no bugs found, 30 hours.
[__] it. You know, I'm, you know, I'm
going through this event.
I'm sitting there, Kate the Great.
she is uh she's talking you know we have
this call happening we're gonna do this
and like doing her spill and I go maybe
I just reach out to someone that I
wanted to hack with and I hack with him
right so I look I go you and I have
hacked before I go maybe Joel would be a
good one but
I don't know if Joel wants to like spend
wants to grind out that many hours so I
click on the list andre is the first one
on that list
yeah cuz the a we got the a up at the
top
it's a it's the it's a hex zero x right
oh yeah okay
I don't even know if That's why, but
it's the first time that I see whatever
it is. And I go, I've always joked
around with Andre. Our tradition when I
was working on Hacker One was he would
not tell me who put an Eminem song for
karaoke walk up to me and go, we're up
in two songs, right? And I go, "Oh my
god, this is meant to be. I got to do
this thing." So, fast forward, you know,
the event happens and honestly, I don't
know what it was, but I don't know if
that's how you are, dude, but when an
event happens or when I'm just hacking,
like I'm in the hacking mode, nothing
else, I can't do anything else. I don't
want to make content.
Yeah, I I I lose my daily routine. I go
to bed. I [__] up my sleep routine.
Same dude.
Uh sorry to editor if I have to edit my
uh cussing, but
you're good.
Um
I'm I can't do anything. So, I'm
grinding out these hours, but right off
the bat, bam, first day we hit with an
SSRF. And it's a very outdated component
that uh I mean, if people have seen it,
you know, me, Alex, and uh Andre won
together. And if you know Alex, you know
exactly what we found, right?
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Of course. I have to
walk. We have to walk those lines of
what we can talk about. But
anyhow, so we get those and I'm like, so
we find this first one. I go, Andre,
this is our event. We got to win now. We
got to win now. And poor guy. I think I
put a little pressure on him.
So I'm going to I'm going to
A lot of momentum though in that.
Yeah. Yeah. Of course, dude. And I can
pull up the text on my phone. I keep
telling Kate, "How does it feel to talk
to the next MVH?" You know, I'm just
Oh my god, he's calling his shot.
I'm just talking I'm just talking out of
my butt, dude. I just I love the [__]
talking aspect of like being a
competitor, right? It's what drives us.
But it's also like [__] talking
manifesting and like pushing yourself.
Right.
Um
[__] talking manifesting, dude. I like
that. That's good.
I got another shirt. But uh yeah, so uh
that happens and then Andre's like,
"Well, dude, if you want to win, we
really got to stop looking at Tik Tok.
Like, we got to focus on the other
company so we can find it." And when we
were testing something on Tik Tok or I
don't know it was Tik Tok or it was
Epic, I kept jokingly telling Andre,
we're going to spam an inline rce into
everything we see. And he keeps telling
me to like f off. He's like, no, that's
not going to happen. That's not going to
happen. We're not going to find an, you
know, command injection like that or an
RC that easy.
Yeah, that's also what I told you.
That's I can't believe it, man.
So, what do you know? We get a it's not
an inline, but it's very similar to the
the aspect of inlining commands into
things, right?
We get that. And then Andre's like I if
you don't know Andre, Andre is
relentless.
If he's I mean this in the most
respectful way, but he's like a dog,
dude. He sniffs something and he's not
going to let it go.
Yeah.
So he's like I we can we can pop this
[__] if you know how he talks.
Yeah.
And this is not to mock him. It's just I
love I I've had this like profound more
respect and love for Andre ever since
the 702 because he was so relentless
like we can pop this.
It's that CTF player mentality, man. All
of the guys that come from the CTF
realm, it's like you give them something
that's kind of sketchy and they just
won't let that [__] go.
Yeah. So, what happens ends up
happening, I'm doing TikTok, he's doing
Epic and we're just talking crap and I
keep inline RC, we're gonna get RC and
it works out, man. It was insane. was I
think we got two to three rccees on Tik
Tok and then we got two rcees on I want
to say two to three RC's on the other
one and then like couple of highs that
were like memory issues and it's on the
same application. We didn't move on move
on from it and uh Joel was there and saw
how I just couldn't anymore. I showed up
to the event. I was so burnt out that I
couldn't do anything but Andre kept
going on the on the
I was I was so pissed man because I have
spent so much time on this app that you
were talking about and I had even put uh
you know command injection payloads in
the same section of that application but
not in the exact same spot that you did.
Um and of course
you just don't so the thing the funny
thing is like I kept joking with him to
do this and he does it as a joke and
then the root cause was something else.
we he was over complicating it and it
was something that we were just like
this has to be a dupe and when they got
triaged
we're having this moment of like
we're going to get shut down and we're
not going to get our belt
right
but this the moral of the story is man I
think we had two people that really
pulled their weight for each app you
know I really focus on Tik Tok and he
was helping me with some of the Epic
stuff or with the Tik Tok stuff and then
he really owned Epic
and I'm like trying to keep up with him
finding other bugs to like balance us
out and then you have someone like Alex
that's insanely good at what he does and
is just like, "Yeah, I already have this
exploit. Let's do it."
Yeah.
And you know, he helps us out with it.
And I think it just I don't know. It's
it's it was so unreal, man. It was such
an unreal experience. It's 702. It's two
bug bounty programs I've never hacked
on, right? If it was like
um some of the programs I've hacked on
in the past, like an Airbnb or Yeah.
I don't know, an Amazon or something
like that, right?
Yeah.
I would be like, "Yeah, easy. I could
win this." I mean, I don't know if I
could beat Sean, but
Yeah, dude.
Easy. I can beat this. Right.
This was a this was an amazing
performance for sure. What talking I
guess more about the technical details
of this sort of thing and you know in as
much as we can talk about because I know
that the target is is uh you know we've
talked about what the target target is.
Um,
would you say that there was a
a randomness aspect to the payload that
you were using there or or was it like
really you were just putting this, you
know, sort of vanilla command injection
payload into a lot of inputs and the the
the breadth of inputs was the thing that
landed you the bug?
I don't think it's the breadth of the
input so much. Let me break it down. So
there's there's a couple of aspects when
it comes down to like
attacking these like massive platforms
that it's like your it's your Facebook,
it's your Tik Tok, it's your Amazon,
it's your those m just giant, right?
The thing that's really interesting is
approaching those targets with a
business mindset and realizing that
these companies even though they're a
social media platform at their core
or an e-commerce platform at their core,
they attend to businesses more.
Right? Do you have more functionality
for business ads and tracking and APIs
than you do as a user?
And it's the the more functionality it
is, the the higher it is also the
chances of you getting it. Lower the
higher the work it is, the amount of
work you have to do to get those
accounts, right?
I I don't know if you were at the show
and tell I said, "Look, I unlocked all
these because I have a registered
business just for this instance, right?"
Yeah. Can you go through the loops to
set up set up the scope in case?
I go on the calls. I I act like I want I
I almost went as far as for one of the
bug bounty programs as put in like
$50,000 to invest in this thing that
they sell you to get access to. Right.
Because
50,000 is like three bucks, four bucks
if I make it back. Right. Exactly. It's
an investment. But to answer your
question, it was the setup part of it
that, you know, a lot of people were
scared of setting up and it's like I got
to give them my social security number.
It's Tik Tok, dude.
Yeah. Like I know it's scary to give
them your SSN, but they have your
information already if you watch Tik
Tok, right?
Yeah.
So there's that there's that aspect of
it that we went really really for
getting those business tools that are
not hard to do. The other thing is
people have access to these tools, but
they don't fully execute them. So is it
going to cost me 200 to run an ad, for
example, or to list an item to list a
house, for example? Right?
On an Airbnb, you list the house and you
got to book it. It's costing you like $
20, $30, right? Nobody's going to spend
that money to do it unless they see the
the investment that we do. Right. Right.
Most most of our regular bug bounty
hunters aren't going to spend $200 to
$300 to invest it.
Dang it, dude. All right, fine. I I've
got this piece of scope that I really
want to pay $4,000 to access.
I'll spill it with you,
dude. It's so It's so good. We're going
to We're going to Let's go. Hold on.
Let's Let's cut this. Let's go do it
right now.
All right, Ben. All right, Ben. We see
you. Not much of a bug story in there,
was
there? More just a winning story.
I'm excited for him, man. That was an
MVH he definitely deserves. And they
popped some crazy bugs at that event.
But obviously, when you talk about the
target, you can't talk about the
technical details too much or else it'll
it'll um you know, you'll give away too
much. So,
yeah. Yeah. Got to keep got to keep some
secrets, you know.
Got to keep it tight. All right. Well,
props to you, Ben, for that one. And
last but not least, we have Mr. Reszo.
Let's see what he's got.
So Evan Connley reached out to me. He's
another uh upand cominging hacker who's
been doing a great uh a lot, you know, a
lot of great bugs lately. And he had a
serverside template injection in
that he could not uh actually you know
find something actionable or some sort
of impact and it was because there's um
you know not a lot of data online about
it and then also the functions are kind
of esoteric and the the um the format is
actually kind of tough to mess with.
Anyways, he reached out to me. We
noodled on it for a while and we had a
breakthrough. I figured out that you
could basically fetch content with a
function called HTTP get and um and then
he actually we ended up reaching out to
Shubs and Shubs showed us that you can
do what basically an eval which in this
marketing templating language is
actually called treat as content.
So the payload we only had,
you know, we only had like 30 characters
or something and it the format's kind of
weird. You have to use like um what are
those called? the percent symbols to
like start and end it and you have to
have the function wrapped in the other
function and so you had to use like a
you know four or five character domain
um and then you had to use two functions
but what's neat is you basically have
the payload on your server then the HTTP
get fetches that in and then you know
the eval which is actually treat as
content executes your um you know your
script or your payload to execute or to
xfill the data and so it was in a uh the
title of the email and so it looks
hilarious because there's these like you
know 10,000line titles in my email of
nothing but user PII at this point.
Dude, that's amazing. Okay, so when it
when it was run with through treat as
content, was that like sort of double
evaluation? Would it would have become
like another template if it was treated
as content or was it really just evaling
the AMPScript that was coming back from
HTTP get?
No. Yeah, it had to be a new template.
So you you would reuse like a templating
language again and then execute as a new
template. I'm a little surprised that
that's even a part of the language.
Yeah,
seemed a little sus, but may I mean I'm
sure it's out there in other places.
I've been told that it's not a um a
default configuration. It has to be like
a custom bug introduced by the by the um
company that's implementing it. But
yeah,
very cool, man. Very cool. I love that.
Yeah, those those scenarios where you
have to really like code golf it and and
you have to get it into such a small
little payload, those are just the most
clutch when you finally get like
arbitrary execution. Feels so good,
dude. Yeah, because you know there's
another world where it never occurred
because there was like just one less
character you couldn't use or something.
It feels perfect. You're threading the
needle.
Um, all right, dude. So, that's the bug.
And for for the listeners there, we're
we're going to wrap the whole uh bug
segment from uh all of the top hunters.
So, I hope you guys enjoyed that. And
we're going to roll right into something
that I'm really excited about, guys. We
are launching a new AI plugin called
Shift. Uh, it's for Kaido. And let let
me just let me just be clear about this.
You know, I think there's a lot of FUD
right now in the in the uh in the
community about AI plus hacking. Like,
oh, some people are like, yeah, no, it's
it's not used here at all. Other people
are like, yeah, our jobs are going to be
gone in like a year. Um, but I think one
of the things that is become abundantly
clear to me is that AI can supplement
our workflows extremely well as hackers.
And there was no clearer uh
representation of this uh than cursor in
my opinion when I got first got my hands
on cursor and saw what it could do uh
and how fast it could develop things uh
with with you know even somebody who's
relatively familiar with programming uh
at the steering wheel. I I was just
absolutely amazed and uh so I hit resop
and I was like dude we've got to build
this plugin shift for Kaido where we can
have sort of a similar functionality
integrated directly into um into Kaido
itself. Um so we went down this path and
and started building it. Obviously I'm
not an AI engineer so I hit Reszo up. Um
and yeah I guess Reszo you want to talk
a little bit about your vision for for
the product and uh and where it's gone?
Sure. Yeah. So, I mean, I've been
thinking a lot about AI and security for
years, of course. Um, and I do think
that like so many people just jump
straight to the, oh, I'm going to let
this AI agent hack everything for me,
when in reality, you know, it kind of
reminds me of what you just said a
minute ago. You said, you know, some
people think that AI sucks and can't do
anything or AI is going to take all of
our jobs in a year and, you know, it's
going to be somewhere in the middle. And
I think cursor is the perfect example of
that, right? It's basically empowering
uh developers to be able to develop
things much quicker and take people who
aren't even great developers and turning
them into um into great developers by
letting them build things they couldn't
before. And so yeah, the vision was
definitely the cursor of hacking. when
you when you said that it just like
clicked like that's such a a key term
because everyone knows cursor um at
least you know every everyone who's like
staying up on AI stuff and so it's the
perfect tool you know it's
everybody should know cursor you know
they don't I' I've screamed about it
from the pod time and time again so if
you don't know cursor at this point
you're doing something wrong but yeah um
yeah so we've got a couple segments that
we want to talk about here this product
just to be clear everybody this product
is still in beta we are not able to
fully release it to everyone yet because
we got to build out all the
infrastructure and fine-tune everything.
But we are looking for some beta
testers. Um, and we'll link the the link
to the weight list down in the
description. Um, for that, but let's go
ahead and talk a little bit about some
of those beta features that we've
implemented. Um, I'll how about you
start with shift core and I'll I'll talk
a little bit about memory and rename.
Sweet. Yeah. So, shift core is basically
the the main product here. And if you're
using Kaido, um you know, we're not
going to rebuild a proxy from scratch,
especially when there's such an amazing
proxy that exists already.
Yeah.
Um so we're we're um integrating with
Kaido and uh you know, you'll do your
command shortcut and it'll pop up and
it's going to be like a little kind of
window that is open in any of the tabs
and it has dynamic content depending on
what tab you're in and it can take
dynamic actions in any of those tabs. So
obviously we can only support what the
Kaido uh SDK actually supports, but it's
a pretty large set of functionality
right now already. So it can, you know,
it can send requests to replay, it can
modify requests, it can send them for
you, it can create fuzzing requests via
automate, it can it can set up match
replace rules for you. Um it's pretty
quick and also it's pretty smooth and
when it works, it feels really nice.
like it has a similar feeling to how
cursor feels in the sense that it it
makes you feel like you're moving at the
speed of light, you know, at the speed
of thought. It's like do this and it
just happens. Um, and so there's of
course a lot of rough edges and a lot of
features we want to add down the road,
but it's working really well right now.
And so yeah, the cursor core or the
shift core is the is the bit that um
does the majority of the lifting of the
work.
Yeah. Yeah. And we named it shift
because we have it uh bound by default
to shift space and and uh I don't know.
So, I don't know. We'll see how that
goes, Reszo. Because like I don't hit
that very often, like on accident, but I
do know that some people will like
they'll be typing and then they'll like
try to capitalize something and they'll
type a character and then they'll space
and and it'll and it'll pop up. So,
we'll we'll we'll see if that works for
everybody, but of course, the the
keybinding will be rebindable if that
doesn't work for you. Um, that's right.
And yeah, man. I mean, just like you
said, I think one of the big things for
me with Shift was the fact that you can
just seamlessly do things on other tabs
of Kaido without it affecting your
workflow. So, I'm in replay, I'm in HTTP
history or whatever, and I'm I see, oh,
I need to match and replace that. I can
literally just highlight it, pop open
the shift box, and say, "Hey, match and
replace this to XYZ." And boom, the
match and replace rule is in in Kaido
built in. it knows exactly where it is
in the context, you know, in the
response body or whether it's in a
header or wherever. Um, so I think
there's a there's a lot of value to
that. Um,
yeah, I've been using it a lot for you
know how when you you'll sometimes be
hacking and you'll find like a specific
string like a function name or an API
path and you really want to just be able
to jump to the JavaScript where that is.
And you know, you can open DevTools and
search for it or whatever, but you
already got Kaido pulled up. And so a
lot of times what I'll do is I'll just
say like
show me JavaScript files that have this
string in it and hit enter. And then all
of a sudden it sets the HTTPQL and it
pops up and then I just can like start
browsing the JavaScript right there
immediately.
Yeah. Yeah. It controls the HTTPQL bar.
It controls the search bar in Kaido if
you want to do it. And it can it can
even navigate you to specific stuff,
right? So if you say like, hey, run a
search for XYZ. Then it will navigate to
that page for you in the UI and then
populate the HTTPQL bar with what you're
looking for as well. So it saves you a
click on that end as well. So it it's
pretty cool. There's definitely some
some uh some bugs that need to be ironed
out. So, we built in a feature right off
the bat. So, for any of you guys that
get your hand on it, uh you know, we're
gonna we're going to be sending out beta
keys uh sort of in waves uh moving
forward, but for any of you guys that
get your hands on it, um there is sort
of a feedback mechanism built into it
where you know, you can press thumbs up
or thumbs down based off of what the AI
did. Um and so we'd really appreciate
that additional feedback uh as you as
you use the plugin. Why don't you tell
them a little bit about how you imagine
memory work and how that's going to like
speed up like crosser testing and stuff?
Dude, this is great. Okay, so so we were
kind of uh sort of brainstorming on the
different features for this and one of
the things that was just became
abundantly obvious to me is like wow uh
this AI really excels with unstructured
data. So, uh, we built in this feature
called memory where you can just select
any text throughout Kaido and press like
control shiftm and it will send that
piece of text to, uh, shift's memory and
then whenever you're doing something in
the future where you're like, hey, uh,
you know, I want to build out this HTTP
request, uh, that's one of the the the
features that I'm super excited about
with Shift Core is like you can just
hand it some JavaScript blob and be
like, build the HTTP request body for
this and it will just build out the JSON
like perfectly which is just super oh I
love that. Um and so and what's even
better then is if you have the specific
IDs like say you've got a store ID or an
organization ID or something like that
um if you have that stored in memory
then shift will know right away to take
those values from memory and populate
them into the JSON body that you're that
you're building. Right? So you just
paste in a JavaScript blob and then boom
it's got all the ids. got all of the all
of the JSON structure and everything uh
pre-formatted and inserted right into
the request body for you. Um so that's
the general concept behind memory. And
then um the last sort of aspect of the
of the product that I think is really
cool is shift rename. And this is
something that I'm just going to be
using non-stop I think moving forward.
Like I'm just never going to go back to
having normal replay tabs. um which is
and this is something that I've
mentioned on the pod before when we
finally implemented it which is uh it
this is an automatic replay tab renamer.
So if you go into the settings for shift
uh there will be like a a box where you
can free form describe the instructions
on how to name a specific replay tab. So
uh the default one that's in there is
start with HTTP verb and then give a
consolidated version of the path and
then I give it an example. Right? So
then every time a replay tab is created,
you can set like a certain offset like
wait 60 seconds or do it right away. Um
the AI will go in there and according to
your instructions analyze the request
and then rename the HTTP tab uh the or
the replay tab um according to your
instructions. Um and that just helps so
much with staying organized and uh just
being able to access the request that
you're looking for as soon as you need
it.
Yeah, especially when you go back and
you're looking for a specific request or
a specific thing that you want to retest
or test. That's where it's really going
to come in clutch.
And like you said, if you're if you're a
person who uses a single project to hack
a bunch of across a bunch of different
programs, then you might, you know, set
those instructions to use the host in
the title of the tab. But if you're a
person who's hacking on the same program
the whole time, then you would maybe
want to just use the path. So that's
fully customizable.
Yeah, 100%. All right, cool. So
definitely we've sold them on it, uh,
Reszo. So, you know, uh, hope you guys
are excited about it as we are. Uh,
we've been using it in our hacking. It's
been really helpful. Um, so I'm excited
to see what you all think as well. We've
got a website stood up at
shiftweightlist.com.
You can go over there, put in your
email, join the the beta weight list,
and then um yeah, as soon as we get uh
everything together and get our
infrastructure in place and stuff like
that, we're going to start rolling out
beta access to it. Um, and the
expectation would be, okay, hey, maybe
at this point it's not a uh a paid
thing, uh, but we need to get your your
feedback. uh and you need to give us
granular feedback on how you would use
it and how it's working and how it's not
working. And then eventually uh this is
going to be a paid product because
obviously we have costs on our side from
the AI uh token consumption. So um uh
just just going to throw that out there
and preempt all the people being like,
"Whoa, crazy free AI plugin." Yeah. I
mean, we're not going to put ourselves
thousands of dollars in debt in here to
to run this plugin. So
yeah, and I think it'll make up for the
time save for nearly anyone who's using
it as well if it already feels amazing
and really smooth for us. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. 100%. So yeah, I mean if it
should just be, you know, in the $20 per
month range, um depending on how much
you use it, I guess. And uh yeah, dude.
I mean, if it saves you 30 minutes, you
know, and it's already saved me 30
minutes, you know, like in just a little
bit that I've used it, um then it should
be totally worth your time. So
yeah, and I think it's going to be a
killer feature, too, for Kaido, right?
If you haven't tried it out, it's going
to be the perfect time to try out Kaido.
And then if you're not super familiar
with Kaido, it's great because the AI
can actually just navigate and send
stuff to places for you, even if you
don't know what they're supposed to be
named.
Exactly. Exactly, man. Yeah. So, I'm
excited about it. Um, hope you guys are
excited about it as well. And I think
that is a wrap on the hundth episode of
Critical Thinking. So, um, everybody,
thank you so much for I'm going to get
emotional here at the end. Thank you so
much for 100 episodes of of, uh, of
viewership. Y'all have been an amazing
community and uh thank you for sticking
with us for this long episode of
Critical Thinking.
Well, as one of your biggest fans, well,
one second before you cut off. As one of
your biggest fans who's probably
listened to more episodes than anyone
else,
uh from from the audience, I'll say
thank you uh to you all for, you know,
putting in two years worth of heavy work
and a lot of episodes and time and
effort, blood, sweat, and tears. We've
needed a good uh Bug Bounty podcast for
a long, long time, and it's been amazing
to get to see you all produce one. Dude,
dude, my heart. My heart. All right,
just cut it there. Cut it there.
Wow, dude. Your email is just constantly
getting bombarded with PII after that.
That's nuts.
So much PII in my email. I think I need
a new email after
Yeah, dude. Um, very cool. Well, that
was a great bug. Um, what' you think of
the uh what did you think of the tool
that that we talked about?
Super cool. Super cool. I know that
there's been some AI stuff in Kaido for
a little while, but
this is like uh this is next level. So,
I really enjoyed using cursor like as a
as a product. So, I think it'll it'll
have really cool implications uh when
when added into Kaido in this way. So,
it should be really cool.
Yeah, man. I think it should be I think
All right, dude. That's the end. No,
Joel, the time has come.
The time has come.
All right, man. Do the honors.
One one final. All right. Yeah,
that's the pod.
Peace everybody.
And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
listening. And if you want more critical
thinking content, head over to
ctbb.show/isord.
Join the Discord. There's lots of great
conversations and chats going on over
there. And if you want to support the
show, there's the Discord subscriber
tiers which give you access to master
classes, AMAs, hackalongs, exclusive
scripts, and an exclusive chat channel
with us. We'll see you there.
[Music]